tempurpedic.com 2018-12-20

# Privacy Policy | Tempur-Pedic

This Privacy Policy was last updated February 2016

This Privacy Policy describes the information practices of Tempur Sealy International, Inc. and its affiliates, subsidiaries, and related entities (collectively “ **Tempur Sealy,** ” “ **we,** ” “ **us,** ” or “ **our** ”). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we collect from you, how we use and share such information, and the choices you have regarding our collection and use. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect about you in our stores, through our call center, when you otherwise communicate with us, and when you visit or use our websites, mobile applications, and other online forums (“ **Online Services** ”).

 **Your Consent**

 **BY ACCESSING OUR ONLINE SERVICES, PURCHASING OUR PRODUCTS, AND COMMUNICATING OR OTHERWISE INTERACTING WITH US, YOU ARE ACCEPTING AND CONSENTING TO THE INFORMATION PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  **

 **Information Covered By This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected about you by Tempur Sealy.  As used herein, “ **Personal Information** ” means information that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, phone number or credit card number, and “ **Non-Personal Information** ” ** ** means information that relates to you but does not directly identify you. “ **Information** ” is collectively used herein to refer to both Personal Information and Non-Personal Information.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third parties or any websites that might be linked to our Online Services or products.    

 **Information We Collect**

Tempur Sealy and our third party service providers ** ** collect Information about you from a variety of sources, including Personal Information you provide directly to us when you order, purchase, or register a product, request information or samples, or otherwise communicate with us, and Information we collect about you when you access or use our Online Services and otherwise interact with us.  We also collect Information about you from third parties including other online services and our business partners.  We may combine any of the Information collected about you for any of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

 **Personal Information.**   Personal Information includes your name, address (both billing and shipping addresses), e-mail address, credit card information, and/or phone number. Each piece individually is a piece of Personal Information, and we collect varying amounts of Personal Information based on how you engage with us. For example, some of the places we collect Personal Information are when you order a product from us, register your product, create an online account, submit an application for financing, request or subscribe to catalogues, product information, promotions or other communications from us, contact or communicate with us, participate in surveys, enter contests or promotions, submit a product review, testimonial, comment, suggestion, or other content to us, access or use our pages or accounts on any third-party social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, or Pinterest, and/or otherwise interact with us online or by phone, mail, fax, or in person.  Based on how you interact with us and the information you share, we use the Personal Information we collected to process and communicate with you about your order, ship the products you ordered, process financing applications and credit card payments, enhance your shopping experience, communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other marketing and research purposes. To help protect against fraud and identity theft, we reserve the right to request proof of identification upon any purchase.

 **Information Collected Automatically.   **Our Online Services, email messages, and advertisements use various tracking technologies that may include cookies, log file information, web beacons, location data, online analytics (collectively, “ **Tracking Tools** ”) to automatically collect Information from you.  We, along with our third party service providers, use Tracking Tools for a variety of purposes, including enhancing your online experience and our product offerings.  We treat Information automatically collected as Non-Personal Information.  Please see below for more information regarding the Tracking Tools that we may use.

 _Cookies:_ **   **We and our third party service providers use cookies, which are small files that are stored on your computer and allow websites to remember information about you. ** ** We use cookies to monitor how our Online Services are used, for marketing purposes, and to help personalize and improve our Online Services. 

 _Log File Information:_ **   **Log file information is automatically reported by your browser or mobile device each time you access our Online Services.  This Information may include your IP address, device and software characteristics (such as type and operating system), browser type, Internet service provider, URLs, referring/exit pages, click data, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

 _Web Beacons:   _When you use our Online Services, we and our third party service providers employ web beacons (also known as clear gifs or action tags) which are used to anonymously track your online usage patterns.  In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients.  This information facilitates more accurate reporting and improvement of our Online Services.

 _Location Data:_   When you access our Online Services via a mobile device, we and our third party service providers may access, collect, monitor, and/or remotely store information regarding your mobile device, as well as real-time “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates.   

 _Online Analytics:_ **    **We use third party analytics tools, including Google Analytics, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for our Online Services.  These tools collect Information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit and other Information, which assists us in improving our Online Services and offerings.  For more information regarding how Google collects, uses, and shares your information please visit<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.    

 _Third Party Ad Serving Companies:   _We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Online Services.   Such advertising companies may also separately use Tracking Tools, including cookies, in the course of delivering targeted advertisements to our Online Services. 

 **Information We Receive From Third Parties.** _    _We may receive Information about you from third parties.  For example, if you access our Online Services through a third-party connection or log-in ( _e.g.,_  through Facebook), such third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to us.  We may also receive Information about you from third parties such as our business partners and service providers.  We may also obtain other Information about you such as change of address, contact information, or demographic information from commercially or publicly available sources.

 **Send to a Friend.   **We may give you the opportunity to tell your friends about product information and promotions. If you take advantage of our Send to a Friend option, we ask you for your friend’s and your first names and e-mail addresses to send the information to them that you requested. 

 **How We Use Your Information**

Tempur Sealy uses your Information, including Personal Information, for a variety of business purposes, including:

  * providing our products to you;
  * processing orders and payments; 
  * processing and facilitating financing applications;
  * product registration and warranty purposes;
  * providing our Online Services to you;
  * processing and managing your accounts with us;
  * communicating with you;
  * improving and customizing our products, Online Services, promotions, communications, and advertisements;
  * responding to your inquiries, comments, or postings;
  * customer service and technical support, which may include responding to your requests, resolving issues, and/or troubleshooting problems;
  * for internal operations such as enhancing our product offerings, marketing efforts, and to conduct research and analysis;
  * developing new products and promotions;
  * for marketing purposes;
  * to prevent fraud or potentially illegal activities;
  * to enforce our Terms of Use; 
  * to comply with applicable laws, regulations, and legal process; and/or
  * to protect the security and integrity of our business, brands, Online Services, customers, and third party business partners and service providers.

We may combine all the Information we collect or receive about you for any of the foregoing purposes.

 **How We Share Your Information**

Tempur Sealy shares and discloses your Personal Information under the following circumstances:

  * with third parties that provide a variety of services on our behalf, including the development, maintenance, and support of our Online Services, order fulfillment, processing credit card payments, delivering packages, marketing research and analysis, communications, and customer service;
  * with third party business partners in connection with our Online Services, product sales and fulfillment, and for marketing purposes;
  * to comply with law, a court order, or other legal process, or in connection with a legal investigation or a request for cooperation by a government entity;
  * to enforce our Terms of Use and any other applicable terms, conditions and other agreements;
  * to protect the legal rights and interests of Tempur Sealy, its business partners  and third party service providers, and our and their respective directors, officers, employees, representatives, and customers; 
  * to protect the legal rights, safety, and security of users of our Online Services;
  * to protect against fraud;
  * for risk management purposes;
  * in connection with a corporate transaction (such as a merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution) or proceeding involving the sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of Tempur Sealy’s business or assets.  In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, Personal Information may also be transferred as a business asset of Tempur Sealy, provided that the acquirer will assume the rights and obligations with respect to your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy; 
  * in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable form; and/or
  * in accordance with your consent.

If you apply for financing, we share your Personal Information directly to the bank(s) administering that account for us.

From time to time we might identify entities whom we believe trustworthy and who maintain privacy policies that are materially consistent with ours. In such cases we might exchange, share and/or cross–reference information, including contact information about you that will enable such entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online, in our stores or through our catalogs with publicly available information or information we receive from or cross–reference with these entities, our related businesses, or others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize the shopping experience of you and others with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

 **User Posts/Product Reviews/Share This**

Any Information that you post (1) to our Online Services, such as a product review, testimonial, or comment, (2) to social media platforms such as Facebook, or (3) using a “share this” feature will be seen, collected, and used by anyone who has access thereto, including, without limitation, your user/screen name. You are responsible for all actions resulting from any Information, including Personal Information, which you post via our Online Services or social media platforms.  Please remember that any Information you share or otherwise post becomes public information, is not subject to this Privacy Policy, and Tempur Sealy is not responsible for the results of such postings.  Consistent with our web site terms of use, we may use any information you post to these public venues for Tempur Sealy’s commercial marketing purposes.

 **Your Choices**

We provide you with the opportunity to update and/or delete certain Personal Information and to opt-out of having your Personal Information used or disclosed for certain purposes.  For example, you may 

  * correct or update your Personal Information; 
  * change your preferences for certain communications ( _e.g.,_  catalogues and product offers);
  * choose whether to receive promotions and offers from us; 
  * request that we do not share your Personal Information with third parties for their marketing purposes; and/or
  * request access to your Personal Information. 

You may exercise your choices at the time of your account registration or product order, via your online account, following the instructions provided in communications sent to you, by clicking http://www.tempurpedic.com/customer-service/contact-preferences.asp, or by contacting us at:

Phone: 800-821-6621 (Customer Service)  
E-mail: [privacyquestions@tempursealy.com](mailto:privacyquestions@tempursealy.com)

Mail: Tempur Sealy International, Inc., Privacy Compliance, 1000 Tempur Way, Lexington, KY 40511

Because we plan our communications in advance, it may take several weeks for your request to become effective. If you continue to receive our communications after expressing an opt-out preference, please let us know so that we can investigate the situation. We will, however, continue to send transaction-based communications if you place an order, request a sample, request customer support, register a product, or make similar requests.

Please be aware that if you do not allow us to collect and use your Personal Information, we may not be able to deliver certain products, promotions, and offerings to you.  

 **Data Collection Tools.  **You may be able to opt-out of the automatic collection of some Information by referring to your web browser’s or mobile device’s options or settings menu.  However, doing so may disable many of the portions, features, or functionality of our Online Services.  For example, most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you have the choice to set your browser to accept or reject cookies.  Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences or visit[http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) for more information. 

 **Google Analytics.  **Google provides users choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics by developing an Opt-out Browser Add-on which can be located at:  <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. By installing this Add-on, no information is being sent to Google Analytics.

 **Location Data.  **You may opt-out from allowing us to have access to your location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device, though some features of our Online Services may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled. 

 **Third Party Ad Serving Companies.**   To change your preferences for cookies used by third party ad serving companies, visit <https://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/what-are-my-options>.

 **Information Security**

We seek to keep your Personal Information secure and implement reasonable technical, administrative, and physical safeguards to help us protect such information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. We use industry-standard encryption technology to provide for the security of customer credit card information. However, no method of electronically transmitting or storing data is ever completely secure, and therefore, we cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be accessed, used, or disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your user password and account login information. We encourage you to set a secure password that is difficult for others to guess, and change your password on a regular basis to help ensure your account remains secure.

In the event that any Personal Information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Tempur Sealy will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other action in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

 **Links, Third Party Websites, and Social Media Platforms**

Our Online Services and communications may contain links to other websites and social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, or Pinterest (“ **Linked Sites** ”).  We are not responsible for the privacy practices, policies, or content of any Linked Sites, even if you link to them from our Online Services or communications.  This Privacy Notice does not apply to any Linked Sites.  We have no control over the collection or use of information, including Personal Information, on any Linked Site.  We encourage you to read and understand the privacy practices of any Linked Sites that you visit.

 **Users From Outside the United States**

Our Online Services are provided from within the United States and are subject to the applicable state and federal laws of the United States. If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that your Information is being transferred to and stored in the United States.  Our Online Services and the terms of this Privacy Policy may or may not comply with foreign law, so if you do not agree with this, please do not use our Online Services.

 **California Resident’s Privacy Rights**

Residents of the State of California may request a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed certain personal information (as defined by California law) during the preceding year for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  If you are a California resident and want such a list, please contact us via the  **Contact Us** information provided below.   For all requests, you must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code.  In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you.  You need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response.  Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information

 **California’s Do Not Track Notice:**   At this time, there is no worldwide uniform or consistent industry standard or definition for responding to, processing, or communicating Do Not Track signals.  Thus, like many other websites and online services, our Online Services are currently unable to respond to Do Not Track Signals.  To find out more about "Do Not Track", you may wish to visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

We do not, however, currently track your Personal Information over time and across third-party websites,

or allow third parties to collect Personal Information about your online activities when you use our Online Services for such third party use.  

 **Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly solicit or collect Personal Information online from children under the age of 13 without parental or guardian consent.  Please contact us as provided below in the Contact Us section if you believe we may have collected such information without parental or guardian consent.

 **Email Security**

“Phishing" is a scam designed to steal your Personal Information.  If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking you for your Personal Information, please notify us as provided below in the Contact Us section.

 **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time effective upon posting the revised Privacy Policy, along with the date on which it was most recently updated, on our Online Services.  Please check our Privacy Policy periodically to see if it has been updated.  If a change to this Privacy Policy materially affects the use or disclosure of your Personal Information, we will notify you by placing a more prominent notice on our home page. By continuing to use our Online Services, order products, provide us information, or otherwise interact with us thereafter, you agree to accept such changes to this Privacy Policy.  Please contact us as described below if you would like information regarding any such changes.

 **Contact Us**

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, you can contact us in one of the following ways:

E-mail: [privacyquestions@tempursealy.com](mailto:privacyquestions@tempursealy.com)

Mail: Tempur Sealy International, Inc., Privacy Compliance, 1000 Tempur Way, Lexington, KY 40511
